<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Espresso Making Assistant</string>
    <string name="sendMessage">Send Espresso Tips</string>
    <string name="six_tips">6 Tips for great espresso</string>
    <string name="tip_one">Bean Preparation</string>
    <string name="tip_two">Bean Selection</string>
    <string name="tip_three">Machine Selection</string>
    <string name="tip_four">Proper Tamping</string>
    <string name="tip_five">Brew Temperature</string>
    <string name="tip_six">Extraction Time</string>
      <string name="bean_preparation">Espresso Coffee Ground\n\n

It is better to have a good quality grinder that produces an uniformly
consistent grind than having a very expensive espresso machine while
skimping with a low grade grinder. The most critical part of bean
preparation is the choice of coffee grinder. \n\nUneven grind can cause
issues such as too fast espresso extraction, and channeling in the
coffee puck (as pressurized water will find the least path of
resistance). So if one has limited budget when first starting out
making espresso at home, it is better to spend the money on a good
grinder and paired it with a starter semi-automatic espresso machine.\n\n

Blade grinder is to be avoided at all cost, as it heats up the coffee ground
in the process of chopping the beans. This process makes it impossible
for a uniform consistent fine ground that espresso making requires.\n\n

Burr grinders (either flat burrs or conical burrs) are the better
choices for espresso ground preparation. How fine to grind the coffee
depends on the bean selection and specific espresso machine. It is a
process that needs to be dialed in by trial and error. \n\nThe best test
for grind fineness is extraction time. The grind is said to be dialed
in if the espresso coffee extraction time for a double shot (15g to
18g) is between 25 - 35 seconds. \n\nAgain it is a judgement call, and one
only gets good at dialing in the grinder for espresso with experience.
The fineness of grind also needs to be adjusted slightly when the
barista change to a different blend of beans.\n\n
      </string>
  <string name="bean_selection">
Selecting the Right Coffee for Espresso\n\n

Many espresso blends are based on one or several high quality Brazil
arabicas, some washed, some dry-processed. They often involve some
African coffees for winey acidity or enzymatic flowery fruitiness, or
a high grown Central American for a cleaner acidity.\n\n

Dry processed coffees can be responsible for the attractive crema on
the cup, among other mechanical factors in the extraction process.
Wet-processed Central Americans add positive aromatic qualities.
Robustas, or coffea canephora, are used in cheaper blends, and some
decent ones, to increase body and produce crema. They also add a
particular bite to the cup. The notion that true "continental"
espresso blends have Robusta? Nonsense! In fact the coffee samples
from small Italian roasters I\'ve had (in green form) appear to be very
mild, sweet blends with about 40% Brazil Dry-process, 40% Colombian
and 20%+ Centrals, like Guatemalan. For bite, syrupy or winey fruit,
and earthiness you can use a DP Ethiopian. Its fun to play with
Robusta but I personally don\'t like it too much beyond experimentation
and I personally don\'t enjoy having more caffeine in my coffee than is
necessary.\n\n

A Colombian-based espresso blend offers a sharper, sweeter flavor but
won\'t result in as much crema production.\n\n

Do you want it to be sharper and sweeter, with more aromatics: perhaps
you will want to add Central American coffees. Watch out with
percentages above 25%, particularly if you like a lighter espresso
roast. You will be losing some crema and body.\n\n

Do you want more body and sweetness: use a clean Indonesian like a
Sulawesi or a premium Sumatra. You will be losing some brightness and
at too light a roast level some of the earthy or herbal qualities can
become sharper. You can go up to 50% with one of these and some are
nice even at 100%, but if you are blending it with an other coffee
that has more delicate features (such as floral wet processed
Ethiopian) that you were hoping to highlight, I would not use too much
of one of these coffees for risk of overwhelming them.\n\n

Do you want an earthy aggressive bite and more pungency: try a dry-
processed Ethiopian. Some are brighter and more aromatic with
fruitiness and wineyness. Some have great pungency in the darker
roasts, and are fruitier in the lighter roasts. These produce great
crema. I often enjoy straight shots of these coffees, but keep it to
25% or so in most blends.\n\n

Do you want spicy pungency: try a Yemeni coffee. These add wineyness
too, and great crema. I keep this to 50% or less (normally 25% or so)
in blends. SOme of the nicer ones have an aromatic sandalwood note
that when balanced with the winey acidity produce really rich and
exotic single origin espresso.\n\n

Do you want extreme bite: try an Aged coffee, a Monsooned coffee
(Indian or better yet the Sulawesi Rantepao) or Robusta. Aged coffees
and Monsooned add certain funky tastes that you may love, or perhaps
hate. You just have to give them a try to find out but that is part of
the fun. Robusta --- I would not go there unless you have too. I
personally do not like the added caffeine they bring. They increase
crema, but you also need to keep them below 20% in the blend, I
personally never go above 15% with them.\n\n

Arabica vs. Robusta? Arabica coffees (that means every coffee we sell
except those at the very end of our list under the Premium Robusta
heading) produce a fine crema, with good aromatics, and a lighter
brown-yellow color. Robusta coffees (from the species coffea canefora)
make a greater volume of crema, but it has larger "bubbles" and
dissipates faster. Robusta has about 2x the caffeine of arabica, 2.2
to 2.4% compared to 1.1 to 1.3% in arabica. It can have a very
rubbery-medicinal flavor when there is too much in the espresso blend.
At a low percentage, 10% to 15%, it delivers a nice bite and it\'s
negative features can be minimized.\n\n

Perhaps you\'ll find that the coffee you chose for a base or even one
of the accents are appealing to you as an espresso on their own.
Single Origin Espresso is becoming more prevalent as people are
experimenting with what an espresso can or should be. Thinking about
espresso simply as a brewing method rather than a beverage in and of
itself with predetermined parameters or "rules" to what it is made up
of and what it should taste like can open up the door to a lot of non-
traditional and sometimes exciting flavors in a shot. But there are
definitely coffees that have too much of one quality or another that
in an espresso extraction are not as enjoyable to me because that
quality can become exaggerated.\n\n

There\'s a lot of ways to achieve great espresso. It\'s fun to
experiment and I don\'t know if there is some terminal point where you
achieve the perfect trans-subjective espresso.(Source Sweet Maria\'s Coffee)\n\n
      </string>
  <string name="proper_tamping">
Tamping the ground espresso is one of the most important factors to
brewing the perfect shot.
      \n\n
      The ground espresso needs  to be densely
compacted into the portafilter in order for the hot water to be
uniformly forced through the grounds with the  same pressure
throughout the entire portafilter.

      \n\nIf the espresso grounds are not
evenly distributed into the filter the water  will find the weak spots
resulting in part of the coffee being over extracted and bitter while
the rest of the coffee is under  extracted and weak. With firm and
even tamping, the water has no other option but to flow through the
coffee evenly  creating the perfect espresso shot topped with rich,
golden crema.\n\n

      To create a solid puck, leveling the ground coffee is important. Prior
to tamping, make sure you evenly distribute the  coffee without
packing the grounds or leaving any spaces.\n\n

Uniformly distribute the ground coffee in both depth and  density
around the basket. Make sure no gaps or breaks occur inside or around
the perimeter of the basket. Once the ground espresso is evenly
distributed around the portafilter, grip the portafilter handle in one
hand and with your other hand press the tamper straight down and apply
approximately 30 lbs of pressure* followed by a light twist to settle
any stray grinds.\n\n

If any ground coffee remains on the perimeter of the filter basket,
use your finger to lightly brush them away without disturbing the
tamped shot.  After the shot has been brewed and portafilter removed,
the espresso puck should be solid, relatively dry and evenly
extracted. If the coffee grounds in the filter are watery and loose,
try applying more pressure to the tamp and ensure  even distribution
of grounds.\n\n

Also, check your grind size to ensure the water can pass through at
the appropriate rate. If  the shot is too slow (over 25-30 seconds)
adjust to a coarser grind. If the shot is too fast (less than 15-20
seconds) adjust  to a finer grind. Practice your grinding and tamping
techniques to perfect the art of brewing espresso.\n\n

(*30 lbs of pressure can be compared to the amount of pressure you
would use to twist off a very tight jar lid.)\n\n
      (Source Capresso, Art of Tamping Espresso)
      </string>
  <string name="machine_selection">
There are in general four types of espresso machines for home
baristas. There are as the following.\n\n1. Manual Machines (all steps are controlled by espresso maker)\n\n2.
Semi Automatic Machines (the suggested one for home baristas IMHO) \n\n3.
Automatic Machines (the machine does everything except bean prep and
tamping) \n\n4. Super Automatic Machines (the machine does all the steps
for you)\n\n

Manual Machines:\n These machines can be expensive and require a set of
skills that beginning home barista may not have, and so should not be
selected if one is just into espresso coffee making.\n\n

Semi Automatic Machines:\n These typically feature an automated pump,
automated temperature controls for the boiler, and activation switches
to engage and disengage the pump. It is semi-automatic as the espresso
maker needs to engage and disengage the  pump switch. This is the best
one for home barista who is interested in making great espresso.\n\n

Automatic Machines:\n These feature a pump, automated temperature
controls for the boiler, and automated (and frequently programmable)
preset water volumes selected by pressing a button. Other than bean
preparation and espresso ground tamping, everything else is done by
the machine. These machines are for people that wants to have good
espresso without the hassles.\n\n

Super Automatic Machines:\n These machines does everything with the
press of a button - grind, dose, tamp, brew, and eject the spent
espresso puck. It makes ok espresso, but not great espresso. These can
be expensive and the buyer pays for the convenience.\n\n
      </string>
  <string name="brewing_temperature">
Brew Temperature\n\n

Proper espresso extraction occurs at 90째C to 96째C (195째F to 205째F).
Lower temperatures accentuate acidic origin flavors, while higher
temperatures accentuate bitter roast flavors.\n\n

Single boiler home machines with non-adjustable mechanical thermostats
have their par temperature at the point the thermostat turns off the
heater. You can brew at a lower temperature by flushing a few seconds
of water after the heater turns off; and at a higher temperature by
forcing the heat back on by turning on the steam switch for a few
seconds (turn it off prior to brewing). This is somewhat hit or miss,
but can be improved by calibrating the flush and steam switch time
with a thermocouple thermometer.\n\n

Temperature measuring portafilter Heat exchanger machines are set by
adjusting the pressurestat, doing a sequence of eight shots or so at
your normal rhythm, and seeing where the shot temperature settles.
After that, you should also adjust the flush to get an idling machine
to that temperature. For one-off experiments or single-shot home use,
simply adjust the flush amount.\n\n

Machines with electronically controlled brew boilers can be set from
the front panel without fuss. Vapor bulb thermostats can be adjusted
inside the machine. Both types should be checked with a thermocouple
thermometer to confirm the actual brew temperatures.\n\n

(Source Home Barista.com)
      </string>
  <string name="extraction_time">
For a double shot espresso aim for:\n\n

25 seconds \u0026 2oz (60ml).....20 seconds is too short, 30+ seconds is
too long.\n\n

You should then vary this volume/time, by altering the grind coarser
or finer, tamping, if done reasonably well should not have a
significant effect on shot volume (unless it channels badly), but may
affect when blonding begins.\n\n

The volume is measured using WBC rules as the volume of liquid and
crema, but in a "normal" environment, this type of strict measurement
rule is not so useful, as the amount of crema could vary hugely. But
if your crema settles out to around 8 mm then try to have the 2oz line
around the top or midpoint of the crema.\n\n

This method will allow you to diagnose problems, as in all cases the
shot should be stopped when it blondes. So even if you extract 2 oz in
25 seconds, if it blonded at 20 seconds (and somewhat less volume) you
should have killed the shot and then looked for the cause of early\n\n
blonding.

(Source Home-Barista.com)
      </string>

</resources>
